PROFILE

I bring DC Big Law experience to Silicon Valley. At two international law firms, I advised technology and telecommunications companies on legal and regulatory matters at the State, Federal, and international level. Clients included Internet edge services (VoIP and SaaS), telecom infrastructure, State agencies, and aerospace manufacturing. I have consulted in-house and freelance on policy strategy and data security compliance.

EXPERIENCE

Thomas Strategies – Menlo Park, CA *Principal/Consultant, 2017—Present*

- On sub-contract to NASA, coordinate advocacy efforts before national and international governments on a first-of-its-kind United Nations initiative to integrate oceanographic sensors onto subsea fiber optic cables
- Identify and mitigate regulatory, legal, and policy risks; develop a repeatable process from RFP through governmental consents, technology transfer, and deployment

Jones Day – Government Regulation Practice Group, Washington, DC *Associate*, 2014—2017

- Provided legal advice, regulatory compliance, and risk management for technology and telecommunications companies including Internet of Things devices, communications to mobile platforms (vehicles, aircraft, vessels), terrestrial location services, voice and data services, traditional and nano-satellites, microwave and fiber connectivity
- Represented clients before State and Federal regulators in rulemaking and adjudication proceedings to craft, revise, and interpret evolving rules
- Developed human-readable best practice documents for engineering teams; drafted and evaluated service level agreements; oversaw regulatory due diligence on mergers

Squire Sanders (US) LLP – Communications Practice Group, Washington, DC *Associate*, 2011—2014

 Same portfolio and clients as Jones Day. Advised on legal and regulatory aspects of telecommunications and technology services including rulemaking, adjudications, and ex partes

IBM Corporation – Global Business Services, Washington, DC

Senior Consultant, Cybersecurity and Privacy, 2010—2011

Managed data security and privacy compliance on Federal and private sector engagements

AFFILIATIONS

The Open Organisation Of Lockpickers (TOOOL)

Member of the Board, Chief Legal Officer, 2013—Present

Amateur Radio Licensee – Technician Class (KC3AZB)

EDUCATION

The Catholic University of America, Washington, DC - JD and Cert. in Communications Law, May 2010

Lead Articles Editor, Published Comment - Catholic Univ. Journal of Law and Technology (2010)

Best Oralist - National Telecommunications Moot Court Competition (2010)

The University of California, Davis, CA, Bachelor of Arts, cum laude, Psychology, 2002